Ethel Burns Breed Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Ethel Burns Breed Papers
1964 1970
1.5 linear feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections James A. Cannavino Library, First Floor, Room 134 3399 North Road Poughkeepsie New York 12601 United States
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Ethel Burns Breed was the wife of Henry Eltinge Breed who designed, engineered, and oversaw the building of the Storm King Highway, with the intention of disrupting the natural landscape as little as possible.
This collection contains both written and typed letters to and from Ethel Burns Breed, newspapers, newspaper clippings, booklets, and testimonies, all pertaining to environmental conservation, Con-Ed, and Storm King.
This collection is organized into three series: 1. Letters from Ethel Burns Breed, 2. Letters to Ethel Burns Breed, 3. Miscellaneous.
Donated by Henry Breed.
No accruals are expected.
[Scenic Hudson Collection: Records relating to the Storm King Case, 1963-1981](https://www.empireadc.org/search/catalog/npkmc_221_183)
[Scenic Hudson Decision Hearings Transcripts Collection, March 9, 1977 - December 12, 1980](https://www.empireadc.org/search/catalog/npkmc_222_083)
1. Letters from Ethel Burns Breed
1964-1965
0.5 cubic foot
- February - September 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- October - November 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- January - February 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- March - April 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- May - June 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- July - October 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
2. Letters to Ethel Burns Breed
1964-1965
0.5 cubic foot
- January - May 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- June - August 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- September - October 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- November - December 1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- January - February 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- March - April 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- May - June 1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- July - August 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- September - October 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
3. Miscellaneous
1965-1970
0.5 cubic foot
- 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)